# Matthew Clifford

Junior Front-End Developer

Email: matthewclifford@hotmail.co.uk

Tel: +44 7708 913 089 Address: Hertfordshire, UK

Matthew is a self-taught Front-End Developer with a robust foundation in HTML, CSS and JavaScript, as well as currently acquiring knowledge of frameworks such as React JS, to accompany BootStrap and SCSS. Currently, Matthew is working in the Travel Industry as a H&S Technical Specialist, specialising in the areas of accommodations and excursions. Having worked throughout the world, including Europe, USA, South Africa, Thailand, North Africa and 3 years working and living in Madrid, Spain, Matthew is now looking for his next challenge.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### SENIOR H&S SPECIALIST

#### Expedia

UK: May 2021 to Present

- → Training Creation and provision of training courses within the H&S field, including classroom training, webinars, online training and shadow auditing.
- → Technical Guidance documents related to technical aspects of H&S within accommodations, excursions and land transportations.

#### H&S TECHNICAL ADVISOR, TRAINER AND AUDITOR

### **Checkpoint Solutions**

UK: August 2007 to September 2009 – July 2014 to July 2016 – May 2019 to May 2020

- → Auditing Execution of fire safety, food hygiene and general safety audits within accommodations, excursions and land transportations across the globe.
- → Training Creation and provision of training courses within the H&S field, including classroom training, webinars, online training and shadow auditing.
- → Technical Guidance documents related to technical aspects of H&S within accommodations, excursions and land transportations.

#### H&S TECHNICAL ADVISOR, TRAINER AND AUDITOR

#### SGS Madrid

Spain: July 2016 – March 2019

- → Training Creation and provision of training courses within the H&S field, including classroom training, webinars, online training and shadow auditing.
- → Technical Guidance documents related to technical aspects of H&S within accommodations, excursions and land transportations.
- → Auditing Execution of fire safety, food hygiene and general safety audits within accommodations, excursions and land transportations.

#### **CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER**

#### **OPRO Itd**

UK: April 2011 - July 2014

→ Customer Service Manager - Overseeing all aspects of the company's customer service department including queries and complaints via switchboard and emails, to managing a team of 6 staff within the department.

# CERTIFICATES

- → NEBOSH General Certificate
- → Principles of Fire Safety
- → COVID-19: Infection Prevention & PPE
- → Level 3 Award in Supervising Food Safety in Catering
- → Auditor Training School Travel Forum
- → Travel-life Sustainability in Tourism
- → Legionella and Legionnaires Disease Awareness

## LANGUAGES







SPANISH (B2/C1)

# **EDUCATION**

Music Production - BA(Hons) University of Greenwich Canterbury, UK 09/2004 - 12/2007

- → Music Production BA(Hons)
- → Music Production (HND)